villagevines.com 2012-06-25

# Savored

## PRIVACY POLICY

**Last updated: June 8, 2011**

VillageVines Inc., d.b.a Savored ("VillageVines" or "Savored" or "we" or "us") is committed to protecting your privacy. We created this Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy") to give you confidence as you visit the Savored website or mobile site (the “Savored Sites” or the "Sites") and use the Savored services (the "Services") provided through the Sites, and to demonstrate our commitment to fair information practices and the protection of privacy. Your use of the Sites and the Services is governed by this Privacy Policy and the [Terms of Use](http://savored.com/terms/).

### 1\. ABOUT THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND OUR SERVICES

This Privacy Policy is only applicable to the Savored Sites and not to any other website or mobile site that you may be able to access from the Savored Sites (whether through an advertisement, service, or content link) or any website or mobile site of VillageVines' partners, each of which may have data collection, storage, and use practices and policies that differ materially from this Privacy Policy.

While you may use some of the functionality of Savored without registration, many of the content and Services on the Sites require registration. If you use our Sites without registering, the only information we collect will be Non-Personal Information through the use of Cookies or Web Beacons (please see Section 2). If you choose to register with our Sites, we require you to submit certain Personal Information, which is information that personally identifies you, including, your first and last name, e-mail address, year of birth, username and password, telephone, credit card information and mailing address. You are responsible for ensuring the accuracy of the Personal Information you submit to Savored. Inaccurate information will affect the information you receive when using our Sites and our ability to contact you as described in this Privacy Policy. 

### 2\. INFORMATION WE AUTOMATICALLY COLLECT ABOUT YOU

Even if you do not register with Savored, we collect Non-Personal information about your use of our Sites.

#### Cookies

We use "cookies" to customize your experience on the Sites and, if you create a password, to store your password so you do not have to re-enter it each time you visit the Sites. "Cookies" are small computer files that are transferred to your computer's hard drive that contain information such as your user ID, user preferences, the pages you've visited and the activities you've performed while using the Sites. We do not link the information stored in cookies to any of your Personal Information you submit while on the Sites. You may block cookies or delete cookies from your hard drive; however, by disabling cookies, you may not have access to all of the features of the Sites. Some of our business partners also use cookies to provide us with anonymous data and information regarding your use of the Sites. We do not have access or control over these cookies, our privacy policy does not cover the use of third party cookies.

#### Web Beacons

We or our third party tracking utility company also use "web beacons" to collect anonymous information about your use of our Sites and the websites of selected sponsors and advertisers, and your use of emails, special promotions or newsletters we send to you. Web beacons are tiny graphic image files embedded in a web page or email that provide a presence on the web page or email and send back to its home server information from the user's browser. The information collected by web beacons allows us to statistically monitor how many people are using our Sites and selected sponsors' and advertisers' sites and opening our emails, and for what purposes. Our web beacons are not used to track your activity outside of our Sites or those of our sponsors'. We do not link Non-Personal Information from web beacons to Personal Information without your permission.

#### Traffic Data

We automatically track and collect the following categories of information when you visit our Website: (1) IP addresses; (2) domain servers; (3) types of computers accessing the Website; (4) types of web browsers used to access the Website; (5) referring source which may have sent you to the Website; and (6) other information associated with the interaction of your browser and the Website (collectively "Traffic Data"). We do not link Non-Personal Information from Traffic Data to Personal Information without your permission.

#### Updating Your Personal Information

You may update your Personal Information by logging into your account, clicking on the My Account tab and following the applicable directions.

### 3\. PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU

#### Registration

In order for you to access certain areas of the Sites, we may require you to register and provide us with certain Personal Information. Personal Information includes Contact Data (such as your e-mail address, phone number, year of birth and password). We use the Personal Information that you provide to respond to your questions, provide you the specific Services you select and send you emails about Site maintenance and updates. You may choose not to provide us with any Personal Information. In such case, you can still access and use much of the Sites; however you will not be able to access and use those portions of the Sites that require your Personal Information and registration.

**Inquiries:** Subject to the Privacy Policy, if you contact Savored, we may use any of the information you submit in connection with your inquiry, or any Personal Information and Non-Personal Information when responding to your inquiries.

#### Email to You

We may use your contact data to send you information to contact you when necessary, including registration verification emails, and in conjunction with your use of certain Services. In some cases, when you click on a link or an advertisement in an e-mail, your browser may be momentarily directed to the website of a third party which, acting on behalf of Savored (see Section 5 below), notes or "counts" your response to the e-mail before re-directing your browser to your selected destination; this re-direction process may not be apparent to you. 

#### Market Research

From time to time the Savored market research department, or its operations contractors acting on its behalf, may conduct online research in order to gather feedback about our site and our sponsors through email invitations, pop-up surveys and online focus groups. When participating in a survey, we may ask you to submit Personal Information. This Personal Information is used for research purposes, and is not used for sales solicitations. When a survey is sponsored by a third party, aggregate information of the survey results is reported to the sponsor. Personal Information collected through market research will be used only by Savored and its service providers and contractors and will not be given or sold to a third party without your consent or as otherwise permitted by this Privacy Policy. We will not knowingly accept survey responses from or conduct interviews with any person under the age of 18. In addition to collecting survey responses from our members, cookies may be used to authenticate respondents or to help you pick up where you left off in a survey. If you have cookies disabled you may not be able to participate in some studies. Cookies may be used to connect survey data with Savored site usage characteristics. You will be notified when we would like to use cookies in this way and your consent will be requested for these cookies.

### 4\. SAVORED USE OF YOUR INFORMATION

We may use your contact data to send you information about Savored or our products or Services, to contact you when necessary and in conjunction with your use of certain Services. We may use your Traffic Data to customize and tailor your experience on the Sites, in emails and in other communications, displaying content that we think you might be interested in and according to your preferences. 

### 5\. INFORMATION COLLECTED BY THIRD PARTIES NOT ACTING ON BEHALF OF SAVORED

Certain content and Services offered to you through our Sites are served on websites hosted and operated by a company other than Savored ("Third Party Contractor Websites"). Savored does not disclose your Personal Information to these Third Party Contractor Websites without your consent, but you should be aware that any information you disclose once you access these other websites is not subject to this Privacy Policy. Savored does not endorse and is not responsible for the privacy practices of these Third Party Contractor Websites. You should review the privacy policy posted on any other website to understand how that Third Party Contractor Website collects and uses your personally identifiable information. 

### 6\. LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES

The Savored Sites contains links to third party sites to which Savored has no affiliation. Savored does not share your personal information with those sites and is not responsible for their privacy practices. Some sites may have the look and feel of our Savored Sites. Please be aware that you may be on a different site and that this Privacy Policy only covers our Savored Sites. Should you decide to visit one of these third party sites, we suggest that you read its privacy policy. 

### 7\. DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION

We share certain categories of information we collect from you in the ways described in this Privacy Policy. We share Personal Information and Traffic Data with our business partners who assist us by performing core services (such as website hosting, data storage and security) related to our operation of the Sites and/or by making certain Services available to our users. Those business partners shall be bound to uphold the same standards of security and confidentiality that we have promised to you in this Privacy Policy, and they will only use your Contact Data and other Personal Information to carry out their specific business obligations to and to provide you with Site related services. 

Last, we may transfer information about you to another company in connection with a merger, sale or acquisition by or of Savored. In this event, we will use reasonable efforts to notify you before information about you is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy. Savored does not share, sell, rent or trade your Personal Information with any third parties for their promotional purposes.

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Sites. 

### 8\. INDEMNIFICATION

You agree to defend, indemnify, and hold harmless Savored from all liabilities, claims, damages, losses, and expenses, including attorneys' fees that arise from your use of the Sites. Savored reserves the right, at its own expense, to assume the exclusive defense and control of any matter otherwise subject to indemnification by you, in which event you will cooperate with Savored in asserting any available defenses. 

### 9\. SECURITY

The Personal Information we collect about you is stored on a secure, password-protected server and only authorized personnel have access to your information. We use industry-standard encryption technologies with respect to the receipt and transfer of Personal Information you submit to us on the Site and only authorized personnel have access to your information. Nevertheless, despite our best efforts, no transmission over the Internet and no data storage method can be guaranteed to be safe 100% of the time. 

### 10\. CHOICE/OPT-OUT

If you no longer wish to receive emails, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each email, or by contacting us via the [Contact Us](http://savored.com/contact/) form.  

### 11\. TRANSFER AND STORAGE OF DATA

The Sites are hosted on servers in the United States. Accordingly, if you are located outside of the United States, the Personal Information you provide to us will be transferred to the United States. By submitting your Personal Information, you consent to its transfer and storage in the United States and its use in accordance with the purposes for which it was originally collected.

### 12\. CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS

California Privacy Rights: Under California Civil Code, California residents are entitled to ask us for a notice identifying the categories of personal customer information which we share with our affiliates and/or third parties for marketing purposes, and providing contact information for such affiliates and/or third parties. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a request through our [Contact Us](http://savored.com/contact/) form.

### 13\. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

We reserve the right, at any time, to add to, change, update, or modify this Privacy Policy so please review it frequently. If we do, then we will notify you here, as well as by posting a notice on our Website and/or by e-mailing you. In all cases, use of information we collect is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is collected.
